Georg J.P. Link

https://georg.link/
orcid.org/0000-0001-6769-7867

SUMMARY

My research advances our knowledge in corporate engagement with open source projects. As corporate involvement increases, open source foundations provide guidance and support for open source projects. We only begin to understand the evolution of this triangular relationship. My current research focus is to inform this relationship through research into open source project health and new market mechanisms. My work has been accepted to the Communications of the Association for Information Systems, the Journal for Universal Computer Science, CSCW, ACM GROUP, Americas Conference on Information Systems, OpenSym, HICSS, CHAOSSCon, and MWAIS. My research has been supported by the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, Mozilla, and the Linux Foundation.

I am engaged at both professional and university levels. I volunteered at various academic conferences, was a conference co-organizer for the 2017 Big XII+ MIS Symposium and 2018 CHAOSScon, am currently the Communications Chair for AIS SIGOPEN, and am an active member of the University of Nebraska at Omaha's BRIDGE Lab — a lab dedicated to the advancement of IT design, architecture, and education. Finally, I am an active member in the Linux Foundation CHAOSS project and the Mozilla Bugmark project.

EDUCATION

University of Nebraska at Omaha, Omaha, Nebraska, USA

 Ph.D. in Information Technology Dissertation: Cooperative Signaling Behavior: Signals for Open Source Project Health Advisor: Prof. Matt Germonprez 	planned 2019
 Focus: Open Source Community Health MBA – Master of Business Administration 	2013

• Concentration: Collaboration Science

• Cumulative GPA: 3.9 / 4.0

■ \$1,851.00 - Linux Foundation

Technical University Braunschweig, Braunschweig, Germany

M.S. in Business Informatics
 Thesis: Evaluating Anchored Discussion as a New Tool for Creativity in Online Collaboration
 Cumulative GPA: 1.3 (German grade translates to 3.7 / 4.0)

WelfenAkademie, Braunschweig, Germany

B.A. in Business Administration
 Concentration: Banking
 Cumulative GPA: 1.8 (German grade translates to 3.2 / 4.0)

GRANT FUNDING Total: \$11,415.00

Travel support to Open Source Summit Europe, Edinburgh, UK
 \$805.00 - Linux Foundation

 Travel support to Open Source Summit North America, Vancouver, Canada

 \$2,441.00 - Mozilla

 Travel support to ACM Collective Intelligence, Zurich, Switzerland

 \$1,318.00 - Linux Foundation

 Travel support to Open Source Summit North America, Los Angeles, CA, USA

2018

2017

Travel support to Open Source Summit North America, Los Angeles, CA, USA
\$5,000.00 - University of Nebraska at Omaha

Program: Graduate Research and Creative Activity (GRACA)

• Proposal title: The Changing Nature of Volunteerism in Open Source Communities

SCHOLARSHIPS

Hanns-Seidel-Stiftung	2012 – 2014
■ German Academic Exchange Service (DAAD)	2012 - 2013
College of Information Science and Technology, University of Nebraska at Omaha	2015 - 2016

HONORS & AWARDS

Doctoral Student Service Award, Association for Information Systems
 Best Paper Award, AIS SIG GlobDev
 2017

- Link, G. J.P., & Qureshi, S. (2017). The role of open source in new business formation: Innovations for development. In *Proceedings of the Twenty-third Americas Conference on Information Systems*. Boston.
- Above and Beyond Excellence Award from UNO Student Government

2013

• Rotary Youth Leadership Award (RYLA) Seminar

2008

PUBLICATIONS UNDER REVIEW (2)

- Link, G. J.P., J. Kowal, S. Qureshi (submitted for second round of reviews on 9/17/2018). Open Source in Development: Enabling Business and Services. *Information Systems Management*.
- Link, G. J.P., M. Rao, D. Mari, A. Leak, R. Bodo (initial submission on 9/12/2018). Marktplatz zur Kollaboration und Finanzierung von Open Source Software. HMD Praxis der Wirtschaftsinformatik.

JOURNALS PEER-REVIEWED (1)

2016 <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, D. Siemon, G. de Vreede, S. Robra-Bissantz (2016). Anchored Discussion: Development of a Tool for Creativity in Online Collaboration, *Journal for Universal Computer Science*, 22(10), 1339–1359. https://doi.org/10.3217/jucs-022-10-1339

JOURNALS EDITORIALLY-REVIEWED (2)

- 2018 Link, G. J.P., K. Lumbard, N. Damen, H. Rosser, M. Germonprez, S. Goggins, A. Wiggins, V. Ahuja, J. brier, J. Cohoon, A. Halfaker, J. Howison, D. Marti, G. Newman, C. Østerlund, R. Paik, B. Rother, A. Schecter (accepted 9/3/2018). Open Community Health: Workshop Report. *Journal of Peer Production*, Issue 13.
- 2017 <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, K. Lumbard, K. Conboy, M. Feldman, J. Feller, J. George, M. Germonprez, S. Goggins, D. Jeske, G. Kiely, K. Schuster, M. Willis (2017). Contemporary issues of open data in Information Systems research: Considerations and recommendations. *Communications of the Association for Information Systems*, *41*(Article 25), 587–610. http://aisel.aisnet.org/cais/vol41/iss1/25/

CONFERENCES (14)

- 2018 Germonprez, M., Link, G. J.P., Lumbard, K., & Goggins, S. (2018). Eight Observations and 24 Research Questions About Open Source Projects: Illuminating New Realities. Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction, 2(CSCW), 57:1–57:22.
- 2018 <u>Link, G. J.P.,</u> & Germonprez, M. (2018). Assessing open source project health. Proceedings of the Twenty-fourth Americas Conference on Information Systems 2018. New Orleans, LA. http://aisel.aisnet.org/amcis2018/Openness/Presentations/5
- 2018 Rao, M., Link, G. J.P., Marti, D., Leak, A., & Bodo, R. (2018). A trading market for prices in peer production. Proceedings of ACM Collective Intelligence. Zurich, Switzerland.
- 2018 Rao, M., Link, G. J.P., Marti, D., Leak, A., & Bodo, R. (2018). A Trading Market to Incentivize Secure Software. Proceedings of the 17th Annual Workshop on the Economics of Information Security (WEIS), Innsbruck, Austria. https://weis2018.econinfosec.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/5/2016/09/WEIS_2018_paper_27.pdf
- 2018 Gandhi, R., Germonprez, M., & Link, G. J.P.* (2018). Open data standards for open source software risk management routines: An examination of SPDX. Proceedings of the ACM GROUP'18, Sanibel Island. https://doi.org/10.1145/3148330.3148333
- 2018 <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, & Qureshi, S. (2018). The role of open source communities in development: Policy implications for governments. Presented at the HICSS 2018, Hawaii. http://hdl.handle.net/10125/50190
- 2017 <u>Link, G. J.P.</u> (2017). The value of engaging with open source communities. In *OpenSym '17 Companion*. Galway, Ireland: ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/3126673.3126679
- 2017 <u>Link, G. J.P.,</u> & Jeske, D. (2017). Understanding organization and open source community relations through the Attraction-Selection-Attrition Model. In *OpenSym '17 Companion*. Galway, Ireland: ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/3125433.3125472
- 2017 <u>Link, G. J.P.,</u> & Qureshi, S. (2017). The role of open source in new business formation: Innovations for development. In *Proceedings of the Twenty-third Americas Conference on Information Systems*. Boston. Retrieved from http://aisel.aisnet.org/amcis2017/ICTs/Presentations/18/

^{*}Authors in alphabetical order

- 2017 <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, Gill, J., & Khazanchi, D. (2017). Measuring adoption of open source software and practices in organizations: A pilot study. In *Proceedings of the Twelfth Midwest Association for Information Systems Conference*. Springfield, IL. Retrieved from http://aisel.aisnet.org/mwais2017/43/
- 2017 <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, Lumbard, K., Germonprez, M., & Goggins, S. (2017). Advancing open online community science practice: The open community data exchange. In *Proceedings of the Twelfth Midwest Association for Information Systems Conference*. Springfield, IL. http://aisel.aisnet.org/mwais2017/44
- 2016 Link, G. J.P., Germonprez, M., Goggins, S., Hemsley, J., Rand, B., & Squire, M. (2016). The Open Community Data Exchange: Advancing data sharing and discovery in open online community science. In *OpenSym '16 Companion*. Berlin, Germany: ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/2962132. 2962142
- 2016 Link, G. J.P., & Germonprez, M. (2016). Understanding open source communities as complex adaptive systems: A case of the R Project community. In AMCIS 2016 Proceedings. San Diego, CA. Retrieved from http://aisel.aisnet.org/amcis2016/Open/Presentations/7/
- 2015 Link, G. J.P., Siemon, D., de Vreede, G.-J., & Robra-Bissantz, S. (2015). Evaluating Anchored Discussion to Foster Creativity in Online Collaboration. In N. Baloian, Y. Zorian, P. Taslakian, & S. Shoukouryan (Eds.), Collaboration and Technology (pp. 28–44). Springer International Publishing. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-22747-4_3

OTHER PUBLICATIONS (1)

2018 Ahuja, V., Marti, D., Link, G. J.P., Germonprez, M., & Goggins, S. P. (2018, May 23). How to measure the impact of your open source project. Retrieved May 23, 2018, from https://opensource.com/article/18/5/metrics-project-success

PRESENTATIONS (14)

- 2018 Link, G. J. P., & Lumbard, K. (2018, August). Chaos or CHAOSS: What we hear from the CHAOSS Community. Presented at the CHAOSScon North America 2018, Vancouver, BC, Canada. https://chaoss.github.io/website/CHAOSScon/2018NA/slides/Chaos-or-CHAOSS.pdf
- 2018 Link, G. J.P. (2018, March). Engaging Volunteers and Voluntolds in Open Source Projects. Presented at the 10th Annual Research and Creative Activity Fair, University of Nebraska at Omaha, NE, USA. https://digitalcommons.unomaha.edu/srcaf/2018/schedule/148/
- 2017 Germonprez, M., & Link, G. J. P. (2017, September). BoF: Community Health Analytics for Open Source. Birds-of-a-Feather presented at the Open Source Summit North America, Los Angeles, California. Retrieved from http://sched.co/BCsP
- 2017 Link, G. J.P. (2017, August). Understanding organization and open source community relations through the Attraction-Selection-Attrition Model. Presented at OpenSym 2017, Galway, Ireland.
- 2017 Link, G. J.P. (2017, August). The value of engaging with open source communities. Presented at the OpenSym 2017 Doctoral Consortium, Galway, Ireland.
- 2017 Link, G. J.P. (2017, August). The role of open source in new business formation: Innovations for development. Presented at the Twenty-third Americas Conference on Information Systems, Boston, MA
- 2017 Link, G. J.P., & Lumbard, K. (2017, May). Advancing open online community science practice: The open community data exchange. Presented at the Twelfth Midwest Association for Information Systems Conference. Springfield, IL.
- 2017 Link, G. J.P. (2017, May). Measuring adoption of open source software and practices in organizations: A pilot study. Presented at the Twelfth Midwest Association for Information Systems Conference. Springfield, IL.
- 2016 Link, G. J.P. (2016, December). Moving Open Source Communities: How Foundations Onboard Communities. Presented at the SIGOPEN Developmental Workshop at ICIS 2016, Dublin, Ireland.
- 2016 Link, G. J.P., & Lumbard, K. (2016, December). Communication Technology Selection in a Young Open Source Community: A Case of the Hyperledger Project. Presented at the SIGOPEN Developmental Workshop at ICIS 2016, Dublin, Ireland.

2016 Link, G. J.P. (2016, August). The Open Community Data Exchange: Advancing Data Sharing and Discovery in Open Online Community Science. Presented at the OpenSym 2016, Berlin, Germany. 2016 Link, G. J.P. (2016, April). The Guided Evolution of Open Source Communities. Presented at the 14th Annual BigXII+MISResearchSymposium, Baylor University, Waco, TX, USA. 2016 Link, G. J.P. (2016, March). The Guided Evolution of Open Source Communities. Presented at the 8th Annual Research and Creative Activity Fair, University of Nebraska at Omaha, NE, USA. http://digitalcommons.unomaha.edu/srcaf/2016/Schedule/56/ 2015 Link, G. J.P. (2015, November). The Movement and Commoditization of Open Source Communities. Presented at the INFORMS Annual Meeting 2015, Philadelphia, PA, USA. NSF: Early-concept Grants for Exploratory Research (EAGER) 2018 Title: Securing Critical Software Through Futures Markets; PI: Matt Germonprez; Unfunded proposal. Mozilla Research Grants 2018H1 2018 Title: Experiment on Introducing Project Health Signals and Price Signals in Open Source; PI: Georg Link; Unfunded proposal. Mozilla Open Source Experiments Program 2018 Title: Experiment for Health Signals in Bugmark; PI: Georg Link; Unfunded proposal Alfred P. Sloan Foundation 2017 Title: Open Source Project Health and Sustainability; PI: Matt Germonprez and Sean Goggins; Funded with \$449,351 (2018-2020)2017 **GRACA** internal grant University of Nebraska at Omaha Graduate Research and Creative Activity (GRACA); Title: The Changing Nature of Volunteerism in Open source Communities; PI: Georg Link; Funded with \$5,000 (2017) **GRACA** internal grant University of Nebraska at Omaha 2016 Graduate Research and Creative Activity (GRACA); Title: The Guided Evolution of Open Source Communities; PI: Georg Link; Unfunded proposal. 2014 **BMBF** (German Federal Ministry of Education and Research) Title: DETHIS - Design Thinking for Industrial Services; PI: Christoph Lattemann; Project number 01FJ15100 funded with 1.6 million Euro (2016-2019). University of Nebraska at Omaha, Omaha, Nebraska, USA • Graduate Research and Teaching Assistant 2015 - present • Funded by Alfred P. Sloan Foundation · Funded by Mozilla WelfenAkademie, Braunschweig, Germany Visiting Lecturer for Information Systems 2014 – present Technical University Braunschweig, Braunschweig, Germany 2014 - 2015 Research Assistant Institute of Business Information Systems — Information Management Group 2013 - 2014 Research and Teaching Assistant • Institute of Operating Systems and Computer Networks — Algorithms Group • Comparing Linear Programming Solvers: CPLEX, Gurobi, and COIN-OR Research Assistant 2011 - 2012 Institute of Business Information Systems — Decision Support Group **Managing the Database Environment** 2017 - 2018 University of Nebraska at Omaha, Omaha, Nebraska, USA Organizations, Applications, and Technology 2017 University of Nebraska at Omaha, Omaha, Nebraska, USA

GRANT WRITING

EXPERIENCE

ACADEMIC APPOINTMENTS

TEACHING

EXPERIENCE

2014 - Present

2013 - 2014

Introduction to Microsoft Excel

WelfenAkademie, Braunschweig, Germany

Teaching Assistant: Algorithms and Data Structures

Technische Universität Braunschweig, Germany

PROFESSIONAL UNIVERSITY ACTIVITIES	UNO Mozilla Club, University of Nebraska at OmahaFounder and Vice-President	2018 – Present
	Graduate College Committee, University of Nebraska at OmahaStudent Representative	2016 – 2018
	UCRCA Committee (internal grants), University of Nebraska at OmahaStudent Representative	2016 – 2017
	PhD Student Group, University of Nebraska at OmahaFounder and President	2015 – 2017
PROFESSIONAL ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES	Executive ■ Communications Director, AIS SIGOPEN	2015 – Present
	Organizing (Conference and Workshop) CHAOSScon North America Organizing Committee CHAOSScon Europe Organizing Committee Workshop on Open Community Health OpenSym Program Committee AMCIS Minitrack Co-Chair Minitrack: Peer Production Project Health OpenSym Program Committee and Session Chair SIGOPEN Pre-ICIS Workshop on Open Phenomena	2018 2018 2018 2018 2018 2017
	Reviewing for Journals 2018 Information and Organization Information Technology for Development Journal of the Association for Information Systems	2018
	 Journal of Organizational Computing and Electronic Commerce HMD Praxis der Wirtschaftsinformatik 2017 Information Technology for Development Information & Management International Journal of Entrepreneurship and Small Business International Journal of Human-Computer Interaction 2016 	2017
	 Communications of the Association for Information Systems Reviewing for Conferences 2018: ICIS, AMCIS, OpenSym 2017: AMCIS, ECIS, PACIS, MWAIS, OpenSym 2016: ICIS, HICSS, AMCIS, ECIS 2015: ECIS 	2018 2017 2016 2015
	 Conference Volunteering ACM Group OpenSym Big XII+ MIS Research Symposium International Conference on Information Systems International Conference on Web Intelligence and International Conference on Brain Informatics & Health Coalition of Urban and Metropolitan Universities 	2018 2017 2017 2016 2016
PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS	Association for Information Systems (AIS) AIS SIGOPEN Midwest United States Association for Information Systems (MWAIS)	2016 – Present
	Association for Computing Machinery (ACM)	2016 – Present
INDUSTRY TRAINING & CERTIFICATES	Bankkaufmann ■ Certified by Chamber of Commerce, Braunschweig, Germany	2008 – 2011

 Bankhaus C. L. Seeliger, Wolfenbüttel, Germany 2011 Ausbilder-Eignungsprüfung • Certified by Chamber of Commerce, Braunschweig, Germany WelfenAkademie, Braunschweig, Germany Freelance Web Developer 2007 - 2018 Custom Websites and Web Applications · Drupal, Wordpress, PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript Claas of America, Omaha, NE, USA • Internship in Warranty Department 2013 • Analyzed years of warranty data using SAP export and MS Excel business intelligence features. • Updated and improved usability of online warranty claim submission manual. • Automated monthly reports in MS Excel with VBA-Programming. VDLUFA Qualitätssicherung NIRS GmbH, Kassel, Germany 2011 Java Developer • Programmed a Java-Servlet server/client application for decentralized data management and analysis. **Participated in Open Source Projects** ■ CHAOSS Project 2017 - Present Bugmark 2017 - Present Core Infrastructure Initiative Best Practices Badge 2017 - Present ■ Toolkit for YNAB 2017 - Present Drupal 2009 - 2010OpenOffice.org 2006 - 2009**Attended Open Source Conferences** • Open Source Leadership Summit 2017 Open Source Summit North America 2017, 2018 Open Source Summit Europe 2017 Mozilla Festival (MozFest) 2017 FOSDEM 2018 CHAOSScon Europe 2018 • CHAOSScon North America 2018 ■ English: Native ■ German: Native ■ Matt Germonprez Mutual of Omaha Associate Professor

LANGUAGES

INDUSTRY

EXPERIENCE

OPEN SOURCE

ENGAGEMENT

REFERENCES

Mutual of Omaha Associate Professor Information Systems and Quantitative Analysis

University of Nebraska at Omaha mgermonprez@unomaha.edu

Sean Goggins

School of Information Science and Learning Technologies University of Missouri

s@goggins.com

Associate Professor

Brian Dorn

Associate Professor Computer Science

University of Nebraska at Omaha

bdorn@unomaha.edu

■ Robin A. Gandhi

Associate Professor Cybersecurity University of Nebraska at Omaha rgandhi@unomaha.edu



[CV last updated on 2018-09-26]